{
    "questions": [
      {
        "question": "What is React.js?",
        "options": [
          "A JavaScript framework for building user interfaces.",
          "A server-side programming language.",
          "A database management system.",
          "A CSS preprocessor."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 0
      },
      {
        "question": "Which virtual DOM is used by React.js?",
        "options": [
          "HTML DOM",
          "React DOM",
          "Shadow DOM",
          "Vue DOM"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 1
      },
      {
        "question": "What does JSX stand for?",
        "options": [
          "JavaScript XML",
          "Java Syntax Extension",
          "JavaScript Syntax XML",
          "Java XML"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 0
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the main purpose of React components?",
        "options": [
          "Handling server-side operations.",
          "Managing databases.",
          "Creating reusable UI building blocks.",
          "Optimizing network requests."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 2
      },
      {
        "question": "In React, which method is used to update the component state?",
        "options": [
          "setState()",
          "updateState()",
          "changeState()",
          "modifyState()"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 0
      },
      {
        "question": "What tool can be used for bootstrapping a new React.js project?",
        "options": [
          "npm",
          "create-react-app",
          "webpack",
          "gulp"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 1
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the purpose of the 'render' method in React components?",
        "options": [
          "To define component styles.",
          "To define component props.",
          "To render the component to the DOM.",
          "To define component state."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 2
      },
      {
        "question": "What are React Hooks used for?",
        "options": [
          "Styling React components.",
          "Managing asynchronous operations.",
          "Adding animation effects.",
          "Managing state in functional components."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 3
      },
      {
        "question": "Which lifecycle method is called after a component is rendered for the first time?",
        "options": [
          "componentDidMount",
          "componentDidUpdate",
          "componentWillMount",
          "rendered"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 0
      },
      {
        "question": "In React, what is the purpose of 'props'?",
        "options": [
          "To store component state.",
          "To interact with the server.",
          "To pass data from parent to child components.",
          "To manage component side effects."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 2
      }
    ]
  }